export default {
  id: 'low_1006_3_1a',
  name: '상용한자(3학년-1/음독찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '反', answer: ['돌이킬 반', 'そ(る)、そ(らす)', 'はん、ほん、たん'] },
    { question: '対(對)', answer: ['대할 대', '대할', 'たい、つい'] },
    { question: '軽(輕)', answer: ['가벼울 경', 'かる(い)、かろ(やか)', 'けい'] },
    { question: '重', answer: ['무거울 중', 'え、おも(い)、かさ(ねる)、かさ(なる)', 'じゅう、ちょう'] },
    { question: '寒', answer: ['찰 한', 'さむ(い)', 'かん'] },
    { question: '暑(暑)', answer: ['더울 서', 'あつ(い)', 'しょ'] },
    { question: '登', answer: ['오를 등', 'のぼ(る)', 'とう、と'] },
    { question: '落', answer: ['떨어질 락', 'お(ちる)、お(とす)', 'らく'] },
    { question: '神(神)', answer: ['귀신 신', 'かみ、かん、こう', 'しん、じん'] },
    { question: '宮', answer: ['집 궁', 'みや', 'きゅう、ぐう、く'] },
    { question: '写(寫)', answer: ['베낄 사', 'うつ(す)、うつ(る)', 'しゃ'] },
    { question: '真(眞)', answer: ['참 진', 'ま', 'しん'] },
    { question: '旅(旅)', answer: ['나그네 려', 'たび', 'りょ'] },
    { question: '館(館)', answer: ['집 관', 'やかた', 'かん'] },
    { question: '期', answer: ['기약할 기', '기약할', 'き、ご'] },
    { question: '待', answer: ['기다릴 대', 'ま(つ)', 'たい'] },
    { question: '消(消)', answer: ['사라질 소', 'き(える)、け(す)', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '息', answer: ['쉴 식', 'いき', 'そく'] },
    { question: '終', answer: ['마칠 종', 'お(わる)、お(える)', 'しゅう'] },
    { question: '着', answer: ['붙을 착', 'き(る)、き(せる)、つ(く)、つ(ける)', 'ちゃく、じゃく'] },
    { question: '駅(驛)', answer: ['역 역', '역', 'えき'] },
    { question: '始', answer: ['비로소 시', 'はじ(まる)、はじ(める)', 'し'] },
    { question: '発(發)', answer: ['필 발', '필', 'はつ、ほつ'] },
    { question: '病', answer: ['병 병', 'や(む)、やまい', 'びょう、へい'] },
    { question: '院', answer: ['집 원', '집', 'いん'] },
    { question: '流', answer: ['흐를 류', 'なが(れる)、なが(す)', 'りゅう、る'] },
    { question: '血', answer: ['피 혈', 'ち', 'けつ'] },
    { question: '医(醫)', answer: ['의원 의', '의원', 'い'] },
    { question: '者(者)', answer: ['놈 자', 'もの', 'しゃ'] },
    { question: '薬(藥)', answer: ['약 약', 'くすり', 'やく'] },
    { question: '局', answer: ['판 국', '판', 'きょく'] },
    { question: '号(號)', answer: ['이름 호', '이름', 'ごう'] },
    { question: '全(全)', answer: ['온전할 전', 'まった(く)、すべ(て)', 'ぜん'] },
    { question: '身', answer: ['몸 신', 'み', 'しん'] },
    { question: '遊(遊)', answer: ['놀 유', 'あそ(ぶ)', 'ゆう、ゆ'] },
    { question: '泳', answer: ['헤엄칠 영', 'およ(ぐ)', 'えい'] },
    { question: '急', answer: ['급할 급', 'いそ(ぐ)', 'きゅう'] },
    { question: '速(速)', answer: ['빠를 속', 'はや(い)、はや(める)、はや(まる)、すみ(やか)', 'そく'] },
    { question: '安', answer: ['편안 안', 'やす(い)', 'あん'] },
    { question: '打', answer: ['칠 타', 'う(つ)', 'だ'] },
    { question: '練(練)', answer: ['익힐 련', 'ね(る)', 'れん'] },
    { question: '習(習)', answer: ['익힐 습', 'なら(う)', 'しゅう'] },
    { question: '勝', answer: ['이길 승', 'か(つ)、まさ(る)', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '負', answer: ['질 부', 'ま(ける)、ま(かす)、お(う)', 'ふ'] },
    { question: '投', answer: ['던질 투', 'な(げる)', 'とう'] },
    { question: '球', answer: ['공 구', 'たま', 'きゅう'] },
    { question: '幸', answer: ['다행 행', 'さいわ(い)、さち、しあわ(せ)', 'こう'] },
    { question: '福(福)', answer: ['복 복', '복', 'ふく'] },
    { question: '感', answer: ['느낄 감', '느낄', 'かん'] },
    { question: '動', answer: ['움직일 동', 'うご(く)、うご(かす)', 'どう'] },
    { question: '列', answer: ['벌일 렬', '벌일', 'れつ'] },
    { question: '島', answer: ['섬 도', 'しま', 'とう'] },
    { question: '受', answer: ['받을 수', 'う(ける)、う(かる)', 'じゅ'] },
    { question: '取', answer: ['가질 취', 'と(る)', 'しゅ'] },
    { question: '物', answer: ['물건 물', 'もの', 'ぶつ、もつ'] },
    { question: '品', answer: ['물건 품', 'しな', 'ひん'] },
    { question: '配', answer: ['나눌 배', 'くば(る)', 'はい'] },
    { question: '送(送)', answer: ['보낼 송', 'おく(る)', 'そう'] },
    { question: '商', answer: ['장사 상', 'あきな(う)', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '業', answer: ['업 업', 'わざ', 'ぎょう、ごう'] },
    { question: '鉄(鐵)', answer: ['쇠 철', '쇠', 'てつ'] },
    { question: '橋', answer: ['다리 교', 'はし', 'きょう'] },
    { question: '乗', answer: ['탈 승', 'の(る)、の(せる)', 'じょう'] },
    { question: '客', answer: ['손 객', '손님', 'きゃく、かく'] },
    { question: '住', answer: ['살 주', 'す(む)、す(まう)', 'じゅう'] },
    { question: '所', answer: ['바 소', 'ところ', 'しょ'] },
    { question: '仕', answer: ['섬길 사', 'つか(える)', 'し'] },
    { question: '事', answer: ['일 사', 'こと', 'じ、ず'] },
    { question: '進(進)', answer: ['나아갈 진', 'すす(む)、すす(める)', 'しん'] },
    { question: '路', answer: ['길 로', 'じ', 'ろ'] },
    { question: '転(轉)', answer: ['구를 전', 'ころ(がる)、ころ(げる)、ころ(がす)、ころ(ぶ)', 'てん'] },
    { question: '向', answer: ['향할 향', 'む(く)、む(かう)、む(ける)、む(こう)', 'こう'] },
    { question: '研(硏)', answer: ['갈 연', 'と(ぐ)', 'けん'] },
    { question: '究', answer: ['연구할 구', 'きわ(める)', 'きゅう'] },
    { question: '相', answer: ['서로 상', 'あい', 'そう、しょう'] },
    { question: '談', answer: ['말씀 담', '말씀', 'だん'] },
    { question: '宿', answer: ['잘 숙', 'やど、やど(る)、やど(す)', 'しゅく'] },
    { question: '題', answer: ['제목 제', '제목', 'だい'] },
    { question: '詩', answer: ['시 시', '시', 'し'] },
    { question: '集', answer: ['모을 집', 'あつ(まる)、あつ(める)、つど(う)', 'しゅう'] },
    { question: '意', answer: ['뜻 의', '뜻', 'い'] },
    { question: '味', answer: ['맛 미', 'あじ、あじ(わう)', 'み'] },
    { question: '委', answer: ['맡길 위', 'ゆだ(ねる)', 'い'] },
    { question: '員', answer: ['인원 원', '인원', 'いん'] },
    { question: '君', answer: ['임금 군', 'きみ', 'くん'] },
    { question: '主', answer: ['주인 주', 'ぬし、おも', 'しゅ、す'] },
    { question: '平(平)', answer: ['평평할 평', 'たい(ら)、ひら', 'へい、びょう'] },
    { question: '等', answer: ['무리 등', 'ひと(しい)', 'とう'] },
    { question: '追(追)', answer: ['쫓을 추', 'お(う)', 'つい'] },
    { question: '放', answer: ['놓을 방', 'はな(す)、はな(つ)、はな(れる)、ほう(る)', 'ほう'] },
    { question: '礼(禮)', answer: ['예도 례', '예도', 'れい、らい'] },
    { question: '式', answer: ['법 식', '법', 'しき'] },
    { question: '使', answer: ['하여금 사', 'つか(う)', 'し'] },
    { question: '命', answer: ['목숨 명', 'いのち', 'めい、みょう'] },
    { question: '悪(惡)', answer: ['악할 악/미워할 오', 'わる(い)', 'あく、お'] },
    { question: '筆', answer: ['붓 필', 'ふで', 'ひつ'] },
    { question: '飲(飮)', answer: ['마실 음', 'の(む)', 'いん'] },
    { question: '酒', answer: ['술 주', 'さけ、さか', 'しゅ'] },
    { question: '部', answer: ['떼 부', '떼', 'ぶ'] },
    { question: '屋', answer: ['집 옥', 'や', 'おく'] }
  ]
}
